<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Publish>
  <ModId Value="87190" />
  <DisplayName Value="Road Builder [BETA]" />
  <ShortDescription Value="Create endless road combinations on the fly while you’re playing the game! With a slick and easy-to-use interface, you’ll be able to create the exact road that you need on the spot." />
  <LongDescription>
# Road Builder
**In collaboration with Trejak and BadPeanut**

Create endless road combinations on the fly while you’re playing the game!
With a slick and easy-to-use interface, you’ll be able to create the exact road that you need on the spot.

## Features

* Edit and create any road, in real-time, without leaving your game.
* Roads are unique and automatically saved when saving your city.
* Each road has its own auto-generated, detailed thumbnail.
* Roads are generated in real time, guaranteeing future compatibility with updates to the game.
* Roads are included in your save-game, allowing you to share it with anyone who has Road Builder with ease.
* You can create asphalt roads, gravel roads, pedestrian roads, highways, all three types of tracks, and pedestrian paths.

## Custom Lanes Support

While Road Builder for C:S II does not have the customization capabilities of its C:S I predecessor, this mod is built to support custom lanes once the asset editor arrives.
This in turn will create endless possibilities and styles for your modular roads. This includes different sizes, textures, and functionalities… 

Once custom lane creation is supported, a guide will be released on how to make Road Builder compatible lanes, with compatible thumbnails.


# How to Use
## Creating New Roads
All roads start from an existing network. You have to place a segment to then edit it.
This partially dictates how the generated road looks and behaves, but you'll always be able to change those settings later.


## Using Custom Roads
When you create a road, it is generated as a whole new asset which you can find and use from the road toolbar or the Custom Roads List.
You can also use the Road Builder tool to 'Place More' of the custom roads you created.


## How to Edit a Custom Road
Once you have a custom road, you can 'Edit All Instances' with Road Builder to automatically update all of the segments of that road that you've placed on the map.
You can, however, choose to create a new road based on that existing one. This will instead only update the single segment that you selected.
To do that, simply choose the 'Use As Template' option when selecting a segment.


## Using the Road Builder Interface
### Road Builder Panel
This panel on the right contains a tab for all the Available Lanes that can be used on your custom road, as well as a tab for all your previously Created Roads.
Using the Available Lanes tab, you can browse different types of lanes you can drag and drop onto the Road Layout preview.


### Road Layout Preview
Located in the center of your toolbar, the Road Layout Preview shows all the current lanes that are applied to your custom road. You can click and drag them to rearrange them, hover over a lane to see and apply any options the lane has, or you can click and drag the lane down into the bin to delete it.
On the far right of the toolbar you can also see the buttons to delete the current road, or X out of the Road Builder Interface.
On the far left of the toolbar there is the option to use as a template, or pick another road to edit.


### The Road Properties Panel
The left panel contains the properties of the road you are editing.
The **Category** section dictates the type of road, which is the same as the 'base' that we mentioned earlier.
The category will generally change what lanes are allowed to be used in the road, it will also change the category where the road is placed in the asset toolbar.

The **Addons** section toggles some extra options available for the road, like having raised sidewalks, zoning, etc…


## Advanced User Mode
Found in the game options panel, under “Road Builder” the Advanced User Mode exposes more lanes available in the Road Builder Panel. Some of the lanes may work in unexpected or unsupported ways, so player discretion is advised.


# FAQ
### Can I combine Subway tracks with other kinds of transportation?
The game does not like to mix Subway networks with other kinds of networks. For this reason, you can’t use Subway lanes in other types of networks by default in Road Builder. However, you can enable “Advanced User Mode” to unlock this restriction.

You will still however need to fiddle around to use those networks in the game.


### Can I make custom bridges with Road Builder?
Bridges that have a unique style are not supported. In the future, there might be minimal support for these kinds of bridges.


### What happens if I share my save-game with someone else?

As long as someone has Road Builder, they will be able to load save-games that contain custom roads in them with no extra steps. It will just work.


### What happens if I use cloud save and load the save-game from another computer?

Just like sharing save-games, you can load your save-game on another computer with no extra steps. However, you might run into an issue where road configurations are duplicated because roads are still saved locally. A good idea would be to turn on “Only save used roads” in the Road Builder options.


### How can I share roads with someone else?

Sharing roads is possible, but it is a manual process for now. You can find your road configurations inside:
C:\Users\%username%\AppData\LocalLow\Colossal Order\Cities Skylines II\ModsData\RoadBuilder

Copy the selected road files from your computer to the same location on the other user’s computer. Then they will find the roads in their game automatically.


### Sharing saves on Paradox Mods

When uploading a save to Paradox Mods that contains custom roads from Road Builder, remember to set Road Builder as a required item. You can do this by navigating to Paradox Mods on your web browser;
- finding the save under “My Uploaded Mods”
- edit the current version
- navigate to the “version” tab
- find Road Builder under the “Required Mods” drop down
- save changes


### What happens if I load a save using Road Builder without Road Builder installed?

The save should load, though all custom roads will load in as default grey networks which you can replace with base game roads.


# Help and Support
If you're facing any issues with the mod, please use the discord linked on the right.
This helps us better assist you and avoids your message from getting lost in the comments.
</LongDescription>
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_01.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_02.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_03.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_04.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_05.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_06.png" />
  <Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshot_07.png" />
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/road-builder.1698661/" />
  <ModVersion Value="0.3.2" />
  <GameVersion Value="1.1.*" />
  <ChangeLog>
# v0.3.2
## Hotfix
* Fixed names and descriptions of roads not showing.
* Fixed the base type of group prefabs.
</ChangeLog>
  <ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.gg/E4k8ZEtRxd" />
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/JadHajjar/RoadBuilder-CSII" />
  <ExternalLink Type="crowdin" Url="https://crowdin.com/project/road-builder-cs-ii" />
  <ExternalLink Type="buymeacoffee" Url="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/tdwsvillage" />
  <ExternalLink Type="kofi" Url="https://ko-fi.com/trejak" />
</Publish>